Guide to the Charles Wilkes Papers, 1816-1876 RL.01383
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Fungi 1849 Oct. 9; 1850 Jan. 24; 1850 Aug. 19; 1850 Dec. 23.
Furness, William Henry (1802-1896), 1849 Sept. 4
Gaines, Edmund Pendleton 1836 May 5
Gall, Franz Joseph 1838 Nov. 25
Gales, Joseph (1786-1860) 1849 May 5
Gardeners. District of Columbia. Washington 1849 June 11; 1849 June 22; 1849 Aug. 11; 1849 Aug. 14; 1849 Oct. 31.
Gardens. China 1850 Dec. 29
Gardens. District of Columbia. Washington. Georgetown 1825 Aug. 19
Gardens. Madeira 1838 Sept. 26
Geological Surveys. New York 1844 May 5
Geology. North Carolina Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 3-14
Georges Bank 1837 May 25; 1837 June 25; 1837 Dec. 2.
Georges Bank. Marine Surveys, 1837 May 25; 1837 June 25; 1837 Dec. 2.
Georgia. Political Parties. Loco Foco, 1849 Dec. 21
Georgia. Savannah. Description and Travel 1837 Dec. 31
Georgia. Slaves 1850s
Giants 1839 June 12
Gibbes, Robert Wilson 1851 Nov. 3
Gibraltar. Description and Travel, 1830 Aug. 5; 1830 Aug. 7; 1830 Aug. 9.
Gillett, Ransom Hooker 1857 June 17; 1857 June 18 (on verso of letter of June 14).
Gilliss, James Melville 1837[?] June 25; 1837[?] June 29[?]; 1837[?] Dec. 2; 1837[?] Dec. 6; 1837[?] Dec. 10; 1837[?] Dec. 15; 1837[?] Dec. 19; 1837[?] Dec. 26; 1837[?] Dec. 29; 1838 Jan. 3; 1838 Jan. 6; 1838 Jan. 8 (2); 1838 Jan. 18; 1838 Jan. 22; 1838 Aug. 11; 1840 Nov.; 1848
Gilpin, Henry Dilworth 1847 Dec. 28
Gipps, Sir George 1839 Dec. 2; 1839 Dec. 3; 1839 Dec. 10.
Girard, Charles Frederic 1857 Jan. 15; 1857 June 8.
Glass Manufacture 1850 Oct. 29; 1854 Mar. 23.
Glendy, William M. 1849 Feb. 1; 1849 Dec. 26; 1849 Dec. 30; 1850 Jan. 3; 1850 Jan. 9; 1850 Jan. 14; 1850 Jan. 21; 1850 Jan. 27; 1850 Mar. 14; 1850 Mar. 16; 1850 Mar. 28; 1850 Apr. 21; 1850 June 9; 1850 June 23; 1850 July 24; 1850 Oct. 24 (attached to letter of Oct. 2); 1850
Glynn, James Letter to: 1830s
Gnomonic Projection 1843 Nov. 7
Gold. California 1849[?] Feb.
Gold Mines and Mining 1853 Sept. 29
Gold Mines and Mining. California 1849 Mar. 2; 1849 Mar. 31.
Gold Mines and Mining. New Granada Printed Material: 1852 May 22
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina, 1848 Aug.-1849 Apr. (letters of Charles and Edmund Wilkes); 1853 Apr. 5; 1876 Apr. 8; 1876 Apr. 16.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Alexander Mine 1853 Apr. 19
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Asbury Mine Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9-10,15)
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Brush(y) Hill Mine 1849 Mar. 22; 1854 July 16; 1854 Aug. 20; 1858 Mar. 31.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Caldwell Mine 1849 Nov. 26
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Capp's Gold Mine 1848 Aug-1849 June (scattered, especially see letters of Edmund Wilkes); 1849 Nov.-1850 Dec. (scattered, especially see letters of Edmund Wilkes); 1851 Jan. 1; 1851 Jan. 2; 1851 Mar. 10; 1851 Mar. 19; 1851 June 23; 1851 July 12; 1851 Aug. 3; 1851 Aug. 6
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Charlotte 1849 Jan. 3; 1849 Jan. 3.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Charlotte Hill Mine 1848 Dec. 9; 1848 Dec. 17; 1848 Dec. 27; 1849 Jan. 4; 1849 Jan. 10; 1849 Jan. 21; 1849 Feb. 10; 1849 Mar. 17; 1849 Mar. 21; 1849 Mar. 22; 1849 Mar. 25; 1849 Mar. 29 (2); 1849 Apr. 4; 1849 Apr. 14; 1849 Apr. 20; 1849 Apr. 23; 1849 Apr. 30; 1849 May 6; 1849
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Chatham County 1871 Nov. 1
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Davidson Gold Mine 1848 Dec. 31; 1849 Jan. 20.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Duffie Mine 1853 Apr. 22
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Dunn's [?] Gold Mine 1848 Dec. 31; 1849 Jan. 16; 1853 Apr. 16.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Felt Mine 1849 Feb. 10; 1853 Aug. 21.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Gold Hill Mine 1856 Mar. 16; 1874 Mar. 29; 1874 June 5.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Greensboro 1853 Oct. 30
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. High Shoals Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9-10, 13-15)
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. High Shoals Mine Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9-10)
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Howie Mine 1854 Jan. 28; 1854 July 23; 1854 Aug. 13 (with letter of July 30); 1855 Mar. 4; 1855 Mar. 18; 1855 Apr. 8; 1855 Apr. 17; 1855 May 5; 1855 May 13; 1855 Aug. 24; 1855 Dec. 15; 1856 Mar. 16.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Hunter Mine 1854 July 16
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. King Mountain Mine 1850 Mar. 23; 1855 Jan. 24; 1871 Nov. 1; 1873 Jan. 19; 1874 Mar. 21; 1876 Feb. 21; Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," p. 15).
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Lemon [?] Mine 1849 Feb. 18
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Long Creek Mine Printed Material: 1873 May 5 ("Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 9,15)
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. McCullock Gold Mine 1853 May 30; 1853 Oct. 30.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. McGinn Gold and Copper Mine 1849 Feb. 3; 1849 Feb. 10; 1853 Apr. 16; 1853 Apr. 19; 1853 Apr. 22; 1853 Oct. 30; 1853 Nov. 1; 1853 Nov. 3; 1854 Jan. 18; 1854 Feb. 5; 1854 Apr. 2; 1854 May 21; 1854 Dec. 3; 1854 Dec. 10; 1854 Dec. 22; 1855 Jan. 24; 1855 Feb. 11; 1855 Mar. 4; 1855 Apr. 2
Gold Mines and Mining [?]. North Carolina. Maxwell Mine 1849 Feb. 13; 1849 Mar. 10; 1850 Dec. 16; 1851 Oct. 5; 1851 Oct. 7; 1853 May 7; 1853 Aug. 15; 1856 Mar. 4; 1856 Nov. 18; 1856 Dec. 3; 1857 Mar. 21; Legal Papers: 1860 Aug. 4.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. O'Farrell Mine 1849 Feb. 10; 1853 Apr. 3; 1853 Apr. 5; 1853 Apr. 16; 1853 May 7; 1853 Aug. 21; Legal Papers: 1860 Aug. 4.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Oliver Mine 1849 Apr. 14; 1849 June 22; 1849 July 25; 1849 July 28; 1853 Apr. 9; 1854 Mar. 21.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Rudisill Hill Gold Mine 1854 Aug. 20; 1855 Aug. 17; 1856 May 4; 1856 Sept. 2; 1856 Dec. 21; 1857 Nov. 14; 1858 Mar. 31; 1858 Apr. 21; 1866 Mar. 28; Legal Papers: Undated.
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Saint Catherines Mills 1854 Mar. 11; 1854 Mar. 16; 1854 Mar. 18; 1854 Mar. 21; 1854 Mar. 22; 1854 Mar. 23; 1854 Mar. 29; 1854 Apr. 2; 1854 May 21; 1854 May 29; 1854 June 27; 1854 July 2; 1854 July 9; 1854 July 23; 1854 Aug. 20; 1854 Nov. 1; 1854; 1856 Mar. 31; 1857 Mar. 21; 185
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Tradywick [?] Mine 1853 Apr. 16
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Trotten Hill Gold Mine 1855 Aug. 17
Gold Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Watkins Mine 1853 Aug. 21
Gold Mines and Mining. Virginia 1853 Oct. 23; 1854 Jan. 28.
Gold Mines and Mining. Virginia. Vancluse Mine 1849 Nov. 30; 1853 Oct. 23.
Gold Rush. California 1848 Dec. 12; 1849 Jan. 24; 1849 Jan. 29; 1849 Feb. 1; 1849 Feb. 4; 1849 Mar. 2; 1849 Mar. 31.
Goldsborough, Louis Malesherbes, Letter to: 1832 Feb. 6; Letter to: 1832 Feb. 27; 1848 Jan. 27; 1850 Dec. 3; 1862 Oct. 19; 1862 Dec. 3; 1863 Feb. 3; 1863 Mar. 6; 1863 May 19; 1870 Aug. 25.
Gould, Augustus Addison 1851 Oct. 8; 1857 Jan. 12; 1857 Jan. 31; 1857 Apr. 14; 1857 June 20; 1857 July 17; 1857 Oct. 21.
Graham, James Duncan 1843 Mar. 5; 1843 Apr. 14; 1843 May 5; 1843 July 21; 1843 Aug. 16; 1843 Oct. 27.
Graham, William Alexander 1850 Dec. 23; 1868 Feb. 3; 1870 May 20; 1870 July 6; 1870 July 15; 1870 Aug. 3; 1870 Aug. 13; 1870 Aug. 22; 1870 Dec. 26; 1871 Jan. 20; 1872 Sept. 19; 1873 Jan. 19; 1873 Mar. 6; 1873 May 27; 1874 July 13; 1875 Jan. 31; 1875 Feb. 7; 1875 Aug. 15; 1875 Sept
Grant, Ulysses Simpson 1870 July 15; 1870 Aug. 25; 1870 Dec. 9; 1872 Jan. 10.
Gray, Asa Letter to: 1857 June 3; 1849 Apr.; 1849 Aug. 11; 1850 Apr. 11; 1851 Aug. 4; 1852 June 21; ca. 1852 July 4; 1852 Nov. 22; 1853 Jan. 11; 1857 Jan. 14; 1857 Feb. 7; 1857 May 4; 1857 May 26; 1857 June 18; 1857 June 20; 1859 July 19; 1860 Jan. 3; 1873 Jan. 30
Grayson, John William 1838 Jan. 19
Great Britain. Foreign Relations. China 1850 June 23
Great Britain. Foreign Relations. Hawaii 1850 May 22; 1851 Mar. 28.
Great Britain. Foreign Relations. United States 1838 Jan. 6; 1862 Jan. 16; Writings: "The Surrender of Mason and Slidell"; Writings: "The great international question"; Writings: "In difesa del San Giacinto".
Gregory, Francis H. 1864 Feb. 29; Miscellany: 1838.
Grey, Sir Charles Edward 1854 Apr. 23
Griffin, Charles 1863 Mar. 10
Grinnell, Henry 1874 Dec. 28
Grinnell, Joseph [?] 1844[?]
Grinnell Expedition, First, 1850-1851, 1850 July 24
Gulf Stream 1859 May 14
Gunboats 1862 Aug. 7; 1862 Aug. 12.
Hairstyles 1863 Mar. 15
Hale, John Parker Letter to: 1849 Mar. 19; 1849 Mar. 25; 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan. 26; 1863 Feb. 10; 1863 Feb. 11.
Hall, George [?] Legal Papers: 1836 July
Halleck, Henry Wagner Letter to: 1862 Aug. 21 (enclosed with letter of 1862 Aug. 22; 1863 Jan. 2; 1863 Jan. 4; 1863 May 7.
Hamilton, James Alexander [?], 1842 July 22; Legal Papers: 1835 Sept. 12.
Hanpfield [?] Railroad 1858 May 24; 1858 June 8.
Harbors. Florida. St. Joseph 1836 May 1
Harbors. Peru 1825 Nov. 25
Harbors. China. Shanghai 1850 Dec. 3
Harper, James (1795-1869) 1844 Oct. 12
Harper and Brothers Company, 1843 Feb. 2; 1845 Feb. 23.
Harris, Ira Letter to: 1862 Dec. 14; 1862 Dec. 12; 1863 Jan. 19; 1863 Jan. 23; 1863 Feb. 3; 1863 Feb. 18.
Harris, Townsend 1850 Dec. 3
Hartsuff, George Lucas 1863 Feb. 10
Harvey, William Henry 1850 Jan. 22; 1850 Nov. 6; 1851 Feb. 8; 1857 Jan. 27.
Harwood, Andrew Allen 1863 Apr. 24
Hassler, Ferdinand Rudolph 1834 Dec. 31; 1836 Sept. 7; 1838 Jan. 18; 1842 Oct. 18; 1842 Dec. 5; 1843 Mar. 5; 1843 Mar. 13; 1843 Mar. 18; 1843 Mar. 26; 1843 Apr. 14.
Hatch, Israel Thompson 1859 Feb. 14
Hawaii 1852 Feb. 21
Hawaii. Duels and Duelling 1848 June 5
Hawaii. Education of Women 1841 Mar. 14
Hawaii. Foreign Relations. France, 1851 Mar. 28
Hawaii. Foreign Relations. Great Britain 1850 May 22; 1851 Mar. 28.
Hawaii. Foreign Relations. Russia, 1851 Mar. 28
Hawaii. Foreign Relations. United States 1850 July 12; 1851 Mar. 28.
Hawaii. Governors 1841
Hawaii. Houses 1841 Feb. 14
Hawaii. Kings and Rulers 1841 Mar. 14; 1848 June 5; 1850 June 16; 1851 Mar. 28.
Hawaii. Missionaries 1840 Nov. 8; 1841 Mar. 14; 1841 [?](2).
Hawaii. Politics and Government, 1848 Dec. 12
Hawaii. Hilo. Schools and Academies, 1846 Oct. 3
Hawaii. Wailuku. Description and Travel 1841 Mar. 14
Hawks, Francis Lister 1857 May 24
Hayne, Arthur Peronneau 1830 June 20
Hayne, Arthur Peronneau [?], 1849 June 6; 1849 June 14.
Hayne, Robert Young 1833 July 28
Hayne, Robert Young [?] 1830 June 20
Heap, Samuel Davies 1830 Sept. 3; 1830 Sept. 18; 1830 Oct. 4.
Henry, Joseph 1837 Dec. 1; 1859 Aug. 20.
Henry, Joseph [?] 1849 May 5; 1851.
Henshaw, David Letter to: 1843 Aug. 21; 1843 Aug. 4.
Herndon, William Lewis 1853 May 31; 1853 June 1; 1853 June 3.
High Shoals Iron Works 1866 July 30; 1866 Aug. 1; 1866 Aug. 20; 1866 Sept. 10; 1866 Sept. 19; 1866 Dec. 6; 1866 Dec. 14; 1867 Jan. 30; 1867 Feb. 4; 1867 Mar. 4; 1867 Mar. 5; 1867 Mar. 26; 1867 Mar. 28; 1867 Apr. 4; 1867 May 22; 1867 May 28; 1867 Aug.-Dec. (scattered); 1868 Jan.
Hise, Elijah 1849 Feb. 24; 1849 Mar. 12.
Hitchcock, Edward (1793-1864), 1849 Apr. 30
Hodgson, William Brown [?] 1836 Oct. 9
Hoffman, Ogden [?] 1825 Oct. 29
Holden, William Woods 1870 Aug. 3; 1870 Aug. 22.
Holmes, Isaac Edward 1851 Feb. 5
Holmes, Oliver Wendell (1841-1935), 1863 May 6
Hong Kong. Americans in 1850 June 23; 1850 Oct. 2; 1850 Dec. 3; 1851 Mar. 31.
Hong Kong. Armed Forces 1850 Oct. 31
Hong Kong. Crime and Criminals, 1850 Oct. 31
Hong Kong. Description and Travel, 1850 Oct. 31
Hong Kong. English in 1850 Oct. 31; 1850 Dec. 3; 1851 July 9.
Hong Kong. Governors 1850 Oct. 31
Hong Kong. Politics and Government, 1850 Oct. 31
Hong Kong. Population 1850 Oct. 31
Hong Kong. Social Life and Customs, 1850 Dec. 3
Hooker, Sir William Jackson, 1850 Apr. 11; 1852 June 18 (enclosed with letter of June 21).
Hooker, Joseph 1863 Feb. 12; 1863 Feb. 18; 1863 Apr. 1; 1863 Apr. 14 (part of letter of Apr. 13); 1863 May 7; 1863 May 8; 1863 May 19; 1863 May 22; 1863 May 29; 1863 June 17; Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20.
Hooper, Samuel 1863 Mar. 18; 1863 Apr. 1.
Horsford, Eben Norton 1850 Sept. 7; 1850 Oct. 29; 1850 Nov. 10; 1850 Dec. 3.
Hosack, David [?] 1825 Aug. 5
Hotels. District of Columbia. Washington, 1871 Sept. 8
Hotels. Mexico. Bell's Hotel 1848 Feb. 27
Hotels. New York. New York Writings: "Hotels"
Hotels. New York. New York. French's Hotel, 1860 Oct. 3
Hotels. Ohio. Cleveland. American Hotel, 1852 Aug. 30
Hotels. Rhode Island. Bristol Ferry House, Printed Material: 1856 [?]
Hotels. West Virginia. Wheeling. M'Lure House 1854 Oct. 30
Houses. District of Columbia. Washington, 1849 Nov. 21; 1849 Nov. 30; 1871 May 12.
Houses. Hawaii 1841 Feb. 14
Houses. Madeira 1838 Sept. 26
Houses. Madison House 1851 July 20; 1851 Nov. 4.
Houses. New York. Amsterdam [?] 1825[?] June 1
Houses. New York. New York Untitled, pp. 10-12
Houses. South Carolina. Charleston 1837 Dec. 21
Houston, Samuel 1836 May 5
Howe, Timothy Otis 1870 Dec. 21; 1874 May 1; 1874 May 18; 1874 May 25; 1874 May 28; 1874 June 10; 1874 July 1.
Hudson, Henry Norman 1850 Jan. 1
Hudson, William H. Letter to: 1838 June 5; 1836 Mar. 26-June 18 (several); 1837 May 16; 1838 July 19-1839 June 12 (several); 1839 [?]; 1840 Mar. 27; 1840 Oct. 18; 1840 Dec. 2; 1841 Nov. 27; 1842 Feb. 20; 1842 Mar. 18; 1842 Mar. 21; 1842 June 20; 1842 Dec. 7; 1843 Aug. 4; 18
Hudson's Bay Company 1840 Oct. 18
Hughes, George Wurtz Letter to: 1836 May 24
Hughes, James (1823-1873) [?], 1871 Feb. 15
Humphreys, Andrew Atkinson 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22)
Hunt, Timothy A. 1863 Feb. 28
Hunter, David 1863 Feb. 18
Hurricanes. Bay of Bengal 1851 Nov. 17
Ice Islands 1839 Mar. 31; 1840 Mar. 7.
Ice. Manufacture 1873 Mar. 6
Illinois. Chicago. Description and Travel 1856 Aug. 2; Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter III).
Illinois. Fever River Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Illinois. Galena. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Illinois. Lead Industry and Trade, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Illinois. Mendota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Illinois. Quincy. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XI)
Illinois. Springfield. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter XI)
Indians. Florida 1849 Sept. 30
Indians. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VI)
Ingersoll, Collin Macrae 1853 Sept. 2
Ingerham, Duncan Nathaniel 1863 Feb. 11
Iowa. Dubuque. Description and Travel, Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Iowa. Lead Mines and Mining. Mallet Lead Mine Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Iowa. MacGregor's Landing. Description and Travel Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IX)
Iron 1846 Feb. 3
Iron. Prices. South 1874 [?]
Iron Industry and Trade 1874 [?]; 1876 Feb. 27; 1876 Mar. 26; 1876 Apr. 16.
Iron Industry and Trade. Connecticut [?], 1870 Dec. 16
Iron Industry and Trade. New Jersey, 1836 Aug. 6
Iron Industry and Trade. North Carolina, 1849 Nov. 26; 1867 Jan. 30; 1867 Feb. 4; 1868 Feb. 3; Printed Material: "Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 12-13.
Iron Industry and Trade. Pennsylvania, 1868 Jan. 17; 1868 Feb. 3; 1874 [?].
Iron Mines and Mining. New Jersey 1836 Aug. 6
Iron Industry and Trade. North Carolina, 1857 Mar. 15
Iron Ores 1873 Aug. 27; 1873 Oct. 5.
Iron Ores. North Carolina Printed Material: "Report on the High Shoals property in Gaston County, North Carolina," pp. 4-9
Iron Works 1846 Apr. 2; 1846 Oct. 3.
Ironclads Clipping: Undated (attached to letter of 1862 Dec. 14); Miscellany: 1862 Aug. 1; Miscellany: [?]; Writings: "Iron Clad Vessels".
Irving, Washington 1836 Feb. 19
Isherwood, Benjamin Franklin, 1863 Mar. 6
Italy. Art. Galleries and Museums, 1830 Nov. 9
Italy. Description and Travel, 1830 Oct. 12; 1830 Nov. 5.
Italy. English in 1830 Nov. 5
Italy. Florence. Catholic Church. Chapel of the Medici 1830 Nov. 9
Italy. Florence. Museum of Anatomy, 1830 Nov. 9
Italy. Florence. Museums 1830 Nov. 4
Italy. Florence. Paintings 1830 Nov. 4; 1830 Nov. 5; 1830 Nov. 9.
Italy. Florence. Pitti Palace, 1830 Nov. 9
Italy. Florence. Statues 1830 Nov. 9
Italy. Florence. Theater 1830 Nov. 9
Italy. Lucca. Description and Travel, 1830 Nov. 5
Italy. Naples. Carriages and Carts, 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Naples. Catholic Church. Church of Saint Francis 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Naples. Catholic Church. Saint Martino Church 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Naples. Description and Travel, 1830 Oct. 12; 1830 Oct. 25.
Italy. Naples. Museums 1830 Oct. 12; 1830 Oct. 25.
Italy. Naples. Paintings 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Naples. Quarantine 1830 Sept. 18
Italy. Naples. Sculpture 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Naples. Statues 1830 Oct. 12
Italy. Naples. Theater. Fonda, 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Naples. Theaters. Opera Houses. Opera of St. Carlos 1830 Oct. 12
Italy. Pompeii. Description and Travel, 1830 Oct. 25
Italy. Resorts 1830 Nov. 5
Italy. Roads 1830 Nov. 5
Jackson, Andrew 1830 June 20
Jackson, Andrew [?] 1833 July 28; 1856 Dec. 21.
Jackson City Association 1836 Jan.-July (see especially letters of Henry Wilkes and William H. Hudson); 1837 Feb. 22; 1837 Feb. 27; 1837 May 24; 1837 July 5; 1838 May 17; 1838 June 15; 1838 July 18; 1842 Oct. 18; 1843 Jan. 13; 1849 Apr. 14; Legal Papers: 1835 Dec. 7 (2); Legal Pa
Jesup, Thomas Sidney 1849 June 15[?]
Jewett, Charles Coffin 1849 Mar. 31
Johnson, Reverdy 1849 Apr. 24
Johnston, Joseph Eggleston [?], 1862 Oct. 18
Jones, George (1800-1870) 1857 Sept. 7; 1857 Nov. 12; 1857 Dec. 26.
Jones, Thomas Ap Catesby 1837 Jan. 7; 1837 Feb. 4; 1837 Dec. 7; 1837 Dec. 10; 1837 Dec. 29; 1849 June 1.
Jones, Thomas Ap Catesby [?], 1849 Sept. 4
Juan Fernandez. Description and Travel, 1822 Feb. 13
Judd, Gerrit Parmele 1840 Nov. 30; 1840 Dec. 11; 1840 Dec. 31; 1841 Jan. 24; 1841 (3); 1849 Oct. 10; 1850 June 7; 1850 June 8; 1850 June 16; 1850 June 21; 1850 Oct. 21.
Kearny, Lawrence 1837 Dec. 29; 1837 Dec. 31; 1838 Jan. 13; 1838 Jan. 18; 1838 Jan. 22.
Kellett, Sir Henry 1850 Dec. 3
Kemble, Gouverneur 1825[?] Feb. 19; 1845 Feb. 10.
Kendall, Amos 1834 Dec. 31
Kennedy, John Pendleton Letter to: 1852 Oct. 19 (enclosed with letter of 1852 Oct. 20
Kennedy, Joseph Camp Griffith, Letter to: 1850 Oct. 23 (enclosed with letter of same date); 1849 Mar. 5; 1863 Feb. 22; 1871 June 20.
Kerosene. Manufacture and Trade 1859 Mar. 13; 1859 Mar. 20; 1859 Mar. 24; 1859 Apr. 5; 1859 Apr. 20.
King, George Gordon 1849 Dec. 8 (on letter of Dec. 5)
King, James Gore [?] 1836 May 16
King's Island 1839 Sept. 12
Labor and Laboring Classes 1856 Jan. 29
Labor and Laboring Classes. Irish 1856 Sept. 30
Labor and Laboring Classes. North Carolina, 1856 May 31; 1856 July 24; 1856 Aug. 3.
Lafayette, Marie Joseph Pau Roch Yves Gilbert du Motier, Marquis de 1825 Aug. 9; 1829 Jan. 25.
Lake Calhoun. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Lake Como. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter V)
Lake Erie 1859 July 11
Lake Harriet. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Lake Minnetonka. Minnesota Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter VIII)
Lake of Tunis. Tunis 1830[?] Sept. 3
Lake Pepin Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter IX)
Lake Shore Railroad 1859 July 11
Land. District of Columbia. Washington, 1874 June 9; 1874 June 10.
Land. Sales and Transfers. Michigan, 1836 June 19
Land Plats. District of Columbia. Washington Broadside: 1874[?] May 12 (in Picture Cabinet III-3)
Land Plats. Pennsylvania. Erie 1850 Feb. 23
Land Plats. Pennsylvania. Venango County, 1835 Dec. 25
Land Surveys. Black Mountain 1851 Nov. 3
Lane, Joseph 1849 Mar. 2
Lapérouse, Jean-François de Galaup, Comte de 1863 June 9; 1863 June 17; 1863.
Lathes 1846 Apr. 22
Latitude 1821 May 24; Miscellany: 1839 Dec. 28.
Latrobe, Benjamin Henry (1764-1820), 1825 Mar. 22
Lawrence, Julia (Montaudevret) Letter to: 1852 Jan. 23; Letter to: 1852 Mar. 6.
Lawyers. North Carolina 1876 Apr. 3
Lead Industry and Trade. Illinois Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Lead Mines and Mining. Iowa. Mallet Lead Mine Writings: Trip to the Far West (Chapter X)
Lead Mines and Mining. North Carolina. Silver Hill Mine 1856 Oct. 19
Lee, Fitzhugh 1863 Apr. 14 (part of letter of Apr. 13)
Lee, Henry (1787-1837) 1836 Oct. 9
Lee, Henry (1787-1837) [?] 1825 Mar. 28
Lee, Robert Edward 1863 May 29; 1863 June 17.
Lee Samuel Phillips [?] 1852 Nov. 27
Lee, William Little 1848 June 5
Leidy, Joseph 1852 Oct. 27
Lenox, Walter Letter to: 1851 Apr. 13
Lichens 1849 June 1
Lieber, Francis 1850 May 31
Lighthouses 1837 June 10
Lincoln, Abraham 1862 Oct. 7; 1863 Mar. [?]; 1863 May 7; 1863 May 19; 1863 May 29 (part of letter of May 28).
Lincoln, Abraham [?] 1863 Apr. 8
Lind, Jenny 1850 Oct. 26
Little, Josiah S. 1836 Mar. 30
Livingston, Charles L. 1834 Apr. 12
Locke, John (1792-1856) 1844 Apr. 27
Longitude 1849 Nov. 12; Miscellany: 1839 Dec. 28.
Longstreet, James Printed Material: 1864 Sept. 20
Louis Napoléon, Prince Imperial of the French (1856-1879) 1870 Aug. 25
Louisiana. Camp Sabine 1836 May 5
Lovejoy, Owen 1863 Jan. 9; 1863 Feb. 10; 1863 Feb. 12; 1863 May 29 (part of letter of May 28).
Lovell, Joseph 1828 Nov. 14
Lunar Limb 1838 June 14
Lyons, Richard Bickerton Pemell, 1863 Apr. 4; 1863 Apr. 19.
Macao. Americans in 1850 Sept. 2
Macao. Balls (Parties) 1851 Apr. 19 (with letter of Mar. 31)
Macao. Clothing and Dress 1851 April 19 (with letter of Mar. 31)
Macao. Description and Travel, 1850 June 23; 1850 July 24; 1850 Dec. 29.
Macao. English Abroad 1850 July 24; 1850 Sept. 2.
Macao. Governors 1850 June 23; 1850 June 24; 1850 Sept. 2; 1851 Apr. 19 (with letter of Mar. 31).
Macao. Hospitals 1850 July 24; 1850 Sept. 14.
Macao. Politics and Government, 1850 June 23
Macao. Social Life and Customs, 1850 July 24; 1851 Apr. 19 (with letter of Mar. 31); 1851 Sept. 18.
McCarty, Andrew Zimmerman [?], 1870 Dec. 9
McCauley, Charles Stewart 1848 June 30; 1848 July 8; 1850 Apr. 26.
McClellan, George Brinton 1862 Aug. 12; 1862 Sept. 22; 1862 Sept. 24; 1862 Oct. 7; 1862 Oct. 23 (part of letter of Oct. 22); 1862 Oct. 31; 1862 Nov. 12; 1862 Nov. 14; 1862 Nov. 23 (3); 1862 Nov. 30; 1862 Dec. 3; 1862 Dec. 4; 1862 Dec. 11; 1862 Dec. 12; 1863 Jan. 4; 1863 Jan. 18; 1
McCluney, William J. 1852 Nov. 27
MacDonough, Thomas [?] 1818 Jan. 16; 1818 Jan. 19.
MacDuffie, George 1827[?] Mar. 7
MacKay, John William 1876 Apr. [?]
McKeon, John 1842 Mar. 12
McLane, Robert Milligan [?], Letter to: 1849 Feb. 2
MacLay, William Brown 1845[?] Feb. 4
McLoughlin, John 1840 Oct. 18
Macomb, Alexander 1825[?] Apr. 9; 1836 May 5.
Madeira. Description and Travel, 1838 Sept. 20 (on letter of Sept. 16); 1838 Sept. 26.
Madeira. Gardens 1838 Sept. 26
Madeira. Houses 1838 Sept. 26
Madeira. Transportation 1838 Sept. 26
Madeira. Wine and Wine Making, 1838 Sept. 26
Madison, Dorothea (Payne) Todd, 1837 Dec. 15; 1845 Jan. 13; 1849 July 13; 1850 June 25; 1851 Mar. 22; 1855 Aug. 17; 1855 Sept. 13.
Magnetic Fields 1844 Dec. 9
Magnetic Measurements 1843 June 22; 1843 Oct. 17 (enclosed with letter of Nov. 7); 1843 Oct. 23; 1843 Oct. 27; 1843 Nov. 2; 1843 Nov. 16; 1843 Dec. 2; 1843 Dec. 3; 1843 Dec. 9; 1844 Jan. 21; 1844 Jan. 28; 1844 Feb. 2; 1844 Feb. 6; 1844 Oct. 29; 1849 June 14; 1849 June 29; Misc
Magnetic Poles 1843 Oct. 27; 1843 Nov. 16.
Magnetism. Terrestrial. Observations, 1843 Oct. 17 (enclosed with letter of Nov. 7); 1843 Nov. 3; 1843 Nov. 16; 1843 Dec. 2; 1843 Dec. 3; 1844 July 8; 1844 Nov. 4.
Mail Steamers 1850 May 3; 1850 Oct. 21.
Mallory, Stephen Russell 1856 Feb. 9
Manning, Richard Irvine 1824 Apr. 3
Mansfield, Joseph King Fenno, 1838 Jan. 3; 1838 Feb. 3.
Mantels 1851 Oct. 25
Marcy, Cornelia (Knower) 1854 Oct. 20
Maria II, Queen of Portugal, 1851 Apr. 19 (with letter of Mar. 31)
Martial Law 1862 Sept. 24
Martindale, John Henry 1863 Feb. 18
Martineau, Harriet 1834 Oct. 2; 1836 Nov. 8.